Apoorvi Ravi Sharma

apoorvisharma.2909@gmail.com | +91 9730017434

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Detail-oriented individual with an eagerness to accept challenges while learning and gaining experience from them. Currently pursuing robotics and automation engineering. I am a dedicated individual willing to assist in the activities of an organization to serve the organization and broaden my experience level.

EXPERIENCE

Drivetrain Engineer, Team Prokarters

Jan 2021- Feb 2022

- Successfully designed and drafted the transmission system of the vehicle.
- Helped in the manufacturing and procurement of components.
- Involved in the fabrication of the vehicle(welding).
- Successfully made cost report and contributed to design report that won AIR 3 and AIR 4 respectively in design at the national level event IKR season 6

Skills Gained - Welding, Drafting, Designing, Cost Analysis, DFMEA, DVP, Procurement.

Vice Head of Industrial Relations, Society of Women Engineers.

May 2021- Present

- Organized a workshop regarding awareness of opportunities in Welding and Advancements in Welding Technology in association with Fronius India Pvt. Ltd.
- Helped in the proper functioning of the team and assisted the head of Industrial Relations. Skills Gained - Team and Event Management.

SKILLS

Application Software: Git, Linux, AUTOCAD, Solid Works, Ansys, Fusion 360, Microsoft Office.

Hardware: Arduino, Esp 32, Raspi.

Programming Languages: C, C++, Python, Matlab.

Interpersonal Skills: Leadership, Teamwork

CERTIFICATIONS

- Applied Thermodynamics NPTEL.
- Introduction to Industry 4.0 and Industrial Internet of Things -NPTEL
- Introduction to Robotics NPTEL.
- 2 Days Advanced Welding Training Fronius India.
- Python Basics for Data Science EDX.
- Proficiency in English Amcat Certificate.
- English Comprehension Amcat Certificate.
- Software Development Trainee Amcat Certificate.
- Data Processing Specialist Amcat Certificate.

EDUCATION

Dr. Vishwanath Karad MIT World Peace University (MIT-WPU) Bachelor of Mechanical (Robotics and Automation) Engineering Current CGPA: 9.10/10.0	Pune, India 2019-2023
Millennium National School, Pune 12TH STD - CBSE BOARD-SCIENCE – PCM- 77.4 %	Pune, India 2017-2018
Sinhagad Spring Dale Public School, Pune 10TH STD -CBSE BOARD - 87.8 %	Pune, India 2015-2016

PROJECTS

Design and Development of a Strain Wave Gear Generator

(Ongoing)

 Design and development of a low-cost, sturdy, and reliable harmonic drive for small-capacity motors.

Modular UGV for Surveillance Operation

April 2022 - June 2022

- Design of a traction system for the locomotion of the UGV on plain Terrain.
- Design and development of two 2-wheel self-balancing robot to act as marsupial to the main UGV bot.

Design and Optimization of a surveillance robot

April 2022 -June 2022

- The designing and assembling of a surveillance robot to serve as the first response mechanism for counter-insurgency and logistics operations.
- The project's goal was to make a surveillance robot out of an Arduino Uno board and integrate an Esp32 cam- module as a sensor input.

Robot Programmer - Basic

Feb 2022 – April 2022

- Tinkering and figuring out various ways to program a KUKA KR-10 R 1420 in the central Workshop.
- Successfully learned how to manipulate and work around with a robotic arm in a certain given workspace.

Automatic Light Control

July 2021 - Sep 2021

Designed a system that would sense a warm body and then turn the lights on.

Rigid Flange Coupling

July 2020

 Designed a rigid flange coupling, to connect two shafts, in order to transmit power from one shaft to another.

WORKSHOPS

 Brainwave Robotics by Technex's 20, IIT Varanasi by Innovians Technologies (India) 23 Nov 2019 - 24 Nov 2019

We created a mobile robot as part of a hands-on workshop, and we used an Arduino UNO to operate it using code, a keyboard, and a Bluetooth-enabled smartphone app.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

International French Language Olympiad Secured 10th State Rank Scored

93.270/100

• Elementary Grade Drawing Examination

Received Grade A

Intermediate Grade Drawing Examination

Received Grade B